EXPRMNTL is a documentary film directed by Brecht Debackere.
Knokke, Belgium.
A small mundane coastal town, home to the beau-monde.
To compete with Venice and Cannes, the posh casino hosts the second ‘World Festival of Film
and the Arts’ in 1949, organised in part by the Royal Cinematheque of Belgium.
To celebrate cinema’s 50 year existence, they put together a side program showcasing the medium in all its shapes and forms: surrealist film, absolute film, dadaist films, abstract
film,… The side program would soon become a festival in its own right: ‘EXPRMNTL’, dedicated to experimental cinema, and would become a mythical gathering of the avant-garde…
himself, played by Jonas Mekas.
herself, played by Agnès Varda.
Himself, played by Harun Farocki.
Herself, played by Birgit Hein.
Himself, played by Jean-Jacques Lebel.
Himself, played by Boris Lehman.
Ji.hlava International Documentary Film Festival (Czech: Mezinárodní festival dokumentárních filmů Ji.hlava), also known as MFDF Ji.hlava or
Ji.hlava IDFF, is a documentary film festival that takes place annually in Jihlava, Czech Republic, typically in late October.
The festival was established in 1997 by a group of high school students in Jihlava, led
by Marek Hovorka, who has directed the festival since its inception.
Since 2001, it has been organized by the Jihlava Association of Amateur Filmmakers, which
rebranded as DOC.DREAM - the Association for the Support of Documentary Cinema in 2015.
Ji.hlava IDFF is a founding member of Doc Alliance, a coalition
of seven European documentary film festivals.
During the 2022 festival, over 86,000 attendees viewed films, with more than 36,000
attending screenings in cinemas and nearly 50,000 viewing films online.
The festival featured 376 films in 2022, and over 1,000 film professionals participated in the Ji.hlava Industry
Programme, which includes initiatives such as Emerging Producers, Festival Identity, and Conference Fascinations.
The 28th edition of the festival was held from 25 October to 3 November 2024, and
the 29th edition took place from 24 October to 2 November 2025.
The tone is mind_bending.